<?xml version=1.0 encoding=UTF-8 standalone=no?>
<rss version=2.0>
    <channel>
        <link>TBD</link>
        <title>Amazon News Headliner</title>
        <description>Amazon News Headliner mock RSS feed.</description>
        <managingEditor>Ama Zonn</managingEditor>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2017 20:10:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2017 20:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss\</docs\>
        <item>
            <link>link</link>
            <guid isPermaLink=true>link</guid>
            <title>Don’t Look Now, But Even Buses Are Going Autonomous</title>
            <description>Reno, Nevade may not seem like the place to develop the country’s first self-driving public bus, but Richard Kelley thinks it presents all the right challenges. The buildings are taller than those in the office parks of the Silicon Valley, providing a good visual test for the complex algorithms. The weather is more taxing, arid with occasional snowfall. Then there’s the foot traffic. “You have people who are just walking out of the casino,” says Kelley, the chief engineer at the University of Nevada at Reno’s Advanced Autonomous Systems Innovation Center. “They’re less predictable when they’re walking about.” If you’re teaching a 14-ton machine to navigate urban chaos by itself, Reno’s not a bad schoolyard. On Tuesday, the University of Nevada announced the start of a three-phase project to get a real, live autonomous bus on the road by as early as 2019. The first stage starts June 1 when a sensor-laden, passenger-carrying electric bus built by California company Proterra, starts trawling a 3-mile route along busy Virginia Street. To start, a human driver will do all the work as the bus collects the data needed to navigate this first stretch. In stage two, researchers will use that info to build self-driving systems. By the third phase, they hope to commercialize and license the tech, and conquer even the craziest city streets. You’ve probably heard the hype about self-driving cars. Though smart, rich companies like Google’s spinoff Waymo have spent years racking up millions of miles with the tech, robo-cars remain years from market-ready. Self-driving trucks promise to remake trucking. But buses? Tesla CEO Elon Musk poked his head out of his tunnel to predict that buses will shrink and ditch fixed stops, opting for a Uber-like approach to pick ups and drop offs instead. As more algorithm-happy startups get into the transportation game, others are predicting public transit will go the way of the Model T.</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2017 20:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>Technology</category>
            <author>aarian.marshall@wired.com</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>link</link>
            <guid isPermaLink=true>link</guid>
            <title>Custom status messages are coming to Slack</title>
            <description>AFK, BRB, in a coffee meeting or what not — Slack, with its constant stream of communication, is probably not the the first place you’d drop an away message or status update to keep people informed of what you’re up to. All that is probably something you’d throw in some other threaded internal communications product that sits perpetually at the top of a page or is easily searchable. That’s probably especially true as companies get larger and communication channels get more out of hand. But Slack is hoping to figure out some way to introduce that kind of employee interaction into a product that could quickly devolve into message mayhem in a way that won’t get lost in a stream of messages (or GIFs, assuming they’re not banned in your channels). To do that, Slack is adding its own flavor of status updates and away messages. Users can hover over an emoji next to a name to get an idea of what an employee is up to — such as getting their teeth drilled at a dentist or out at a retreat. They can add a 100-character description of why they can’t respond to a message with an emoji of their choice (like an airplane if the Wi-Fi isn’t working or something to that extent). Perhaps more interesting in this update is that Slack is also opening the feature to third-party developers to automatically set statuses. In a blog post, Slack pointed to a feature that allows Zenefits to automatically set an away message when someone is logging vacation through Zenefits. This is going to give developers yet another touch-point into the platform that is increasingly hot in Silicon Valley but still has to breach into the real world of massive companies that may be sticking to more traditional internal communications channels. Slack earlier this year introduced threaded messages in an attempt to give Slack a more persistent and permanent home for certain conversations. Status updates, to some extent, are also not too dissimilar — they exist as some semi-permanent home for communication of an employee’s current situation in a static way to coworkers. Slack, it would seem, is trying to become more of a home page of internal communication instead of a messaging client. That’s going to be important going forward as it tries to woo people away from existing products. Slack, which at times may seem apprehensive about introducing product updates, seems to also be adding a good deal of incremental features in the past few weeks. Earlier this week it further opened up tools to developers that allows them to make Slack bots more interactive with drop-down menus.</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2017 20:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>Technology</category>
            <author>Matthew.Lynley@tc.com</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>link</link>
            <guid isPermaLink=true>link</guid>
            <title>Toyota’s new robot leg brace can help those with partial paralysis walk again</title>
            <description>Toyota is introducing a new robotic leg brace called the Welwalk WW-1000 that can help patients with partial paralysis affecting one side of their body walk again. The robotic exoframe is worn on the affected leg, with a large motor component at the knee joint that provides just enough assistance to the patient, letting them recover their own walking ability therapeutically over time. The robotic wearable is paired with a custom treadmill and a harness that is anchored above the patient, with medical staff able to watch and control the whole apparatus from a convenient touchscreen input device. The Associated Press reports that the Welwalk system will be made available to medical institutions in Japan later this year, with a rental model that charges a one-time fee of around ,000 and then ,200 after that on a monthly basis. Those costs are not overly burdensome by medial equipment standards, and the system could drastically reduce recovery time for patients overcoming partial paralysis resulting from conditions include strokes. Reductions in recovery time come from how accurate the Welwalk system can be in terms of tweaking the amount of support it provides: Rehabilitating patients affected by this kind of partial paralysis involves gradually stepping back the amount of reliance they have on therapeutic support, until they’re able to walk independently once again. Toyota’s robotic brace includes built-in sensors that know exactly how much support to provide the patient at any given point, letting making sure they aren’t either over-reliant on support, or rushed before they’re ready, potentially resulting in re-injury. Toyota has been working on robotics for many years now, and its Toyota Research Institute arm is devoted specifically to helping create technology that increases independence and quality of life for an aging population. Hyundai also demonstrated a range of personal support robotic wearables last year, and it’s likely to be an increased area of focus among automakers in general as their turn their attention and business focus to overall mobility, beyond just vehicles and transportation.</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2017 20:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>Technology</category>
            <author>Darrell.Etherington@tc.com</author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
