<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <link>TBD</link>
        <title>Amazon News Headliner</title>
        <description>Amazon News Headliner mock RSS feed.</description>
        <managingEditor>Ama Zonn</managingEditor>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2017 20:10:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2017 20:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <item>
            <link>link</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">link</guid>
            <title>This Earth-size virtual telescope could take the first picture of a black hole</title>
            <description>A supermassive black hole lurks at the center of our galaxy, but we've never seen it. We know it's there, and that it has the mass of about 4 million suns, and that the stars in our galaxy revolve around it. But no one could tell you exactly what it looks like. In fact, astronomers have never been able to snap a direct image of any black hole, ever. That's because although the black holes at the center of galaxies are supermassive, they're really far away. It's akin to trying see a grapefruit, DVD, or bagel on the surface of the moon. You'd need a supermassive telescope, 1000 times the size of Hubble, to spot one. Or, maybe, just eight telescopes working together. The Event Horizon Telescope (EHT), which is actually a network of eight radiofrequency observatories around the world, switched on for the first time on April 5. Between now and April 14, the observatories hope to gather enough data to piece together our first snapshot a black hole's event horizon—the "point of no return" threshold after which nothing can escape the black hole's gravity. These telescopes will collect radio waves emitting from the supermassive black hole at the center of the Milky Way, as well as the neighboring galaxy Messier 87, and stitch them together into visual images. The EHT's resolution is said to be about as good as being able to count the stitches on a baseball from 8,000 miles away. Over at Nature, Davide Castelvecchi explains that instead of using just one very big mirror or antenna dish, the technique (called very-long-baseline interferometry) works by merging multiple observatories into "one virtual telescope—with an effective aperture as big as the distance between them." Heino Falcke, an astrophysicist at Radboud University in the Netherlands, told Popular Science that this project wouldn't have been possible just a few years ago. The Atacama Large Millimeter Array, which has been fully operational since 2013, "adds a lot of sensitivity and image quality," he says. "Also, we need to record and store an enormous amount of data—almost half a petabyte per telescope. That wasn’t feasible a few years ago." EHT's goal isn't just to see what our friendly neighborhood black hole is up to. The team, lead by astrophysicist Sheperd Doeleman at Harvard University, thinks that "seeing" a black hole for the first time could help lead to a theory of everything, uniting the laws that govern very small quantum mechanical physics with the laws that govern very big things in the universe. The project also aims to learn more about how these gravitational anomalies pull in matter, and how they generate huge jets of plasma. It could also shed light on Stephen Hawking's hypothesis that information that falls into a black hole must somehow leak back out. After analyzing the vast amounts of data that will be generated by this experiment—about 2 petabytes for each of the four or five nights of observation—the EHT team hopes to have a picture ready in 2018.</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2017 20:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>Science</category>
            <author>SarahFecht@popsci.com</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>link</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">link</guid>
            <title>The Busy Little Robot on a Quest to Help Humanity Feed Itself</title>
            <description>I'm not going to tell you to stop having babies, but the hard truth is that the population of Homo sapiens will skyrocket to perhaps 9 billion by 2050. More people means more emissions, which means runaway global warming, which means the agriculture required to feed those 9 billion people is in peril. Call humanity a cancer, call it a virus, but neither of those things ever invented a robot to eyeball corn plants. Allow me to introduce you to Vinobot, the little rover on a mission to make sure crops weather global warming. Vinobot has a partner in this, a solar-powered tower that keeps watch over a field. Using 3-D cameras, it builds a picture of the crops, looking for individual plants under stress. Should the tower spot something awry, it dispatches Vinobot. The rover uses its robotic arm to create a detailed 3-D model of the plant, showing scientists the exact angles of leaves, for instance, to determine how different kinds of corn handle drought. (Corn leaves tend to droop in the heat, reducing the surface area exposed to the sun.) Vinobot also collects humidity, light intensity, and temperature data at the bottom, middle, and top of the shoot. "We collect those at three different heights because we’re trying to study how the density of planting is affecting the individual plants," says the robot’s developer, Gui DeSouza, of the University of Missouri. If humanity expects to feed itself in the coming decades, it must figure out how to increase yields, which means packing more crops into the same amount of land. All of this data will help scientists understand how corn will fare in a warming world. And corn is just the start: Vinobot could trundle into fields of other crops as well. "We have a growing population that demands more and more food," says DeSouza. "We have to produce more, we have to optimize the field, we have to optimize the planting, we have to increase the density. How are we going to adapt to those needs?" Robots are certainly a start. Because good luck getting humans to stop making babies.</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 20:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>Science</category>
            <author>Matt.Simon@wired.com</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <link>link</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">link</guid>
            <title>Mars’ Ionosphere: Cold, Lifeless, and Filled With Heavy Metals</title>
            <description>Mars is earth's inhospitable cousin. And like anybody with a wayward family member, Earthlings can’t help trying to figure out what went wrong. So people throw a lot of money at the red planet, usually in the form of spacecraft. NASA’s Maven mission explores Mars’ upper atmosphere, puzzling over how a planet that was once wet and potentially habitable ended up a dry, cold desert world. Metal could solve the mystery. In a new study, Maven mission scientists found that Mars’ ionosphere is full of metal ions, tiny charged flecks of meteorite pulled apart by atmospheric forces. Because those ions are hardy and trackable, scientists can use them to study the mysterious dynamics of the planets’ upper atmosphere, including its tendency to escape out into space. Plus, scientists have already observed similar metal ions at work in Earth’s (very different) atmosphere. Scientists sorting out how these upper layers sort themselves out are rethinking their assumptions about how worlds work. Earth and Mars get their metal ions from the same source: the constant hail of micrometeorites beating down on their atmospheres. As the flecks of meteorite burn up, charged particles in the atmosphere rip electrons away from metal atoms, turning them into positively charged ions. (Maven has found iron, sodium, and magnesium ions in Mars’ atmosphere.) And that’s not just interesting trivia: "It’s like dropping ink in water," says Mehdi Benna, planetary scientist at NASA’s Goddard Space Flight Center. "You can see which way the current moves." Before Maven detected these ions, the dynamics of Mars’ upper atmosphere were darn near invisible, which makes gravity waves or a phenomenon like atmospheric escape pretty hard to study. "We were surprised to see these metal ions in the Martian atmosphere," says Benna. That’s because Mars doesn’t have Earth’s strong, planet-wide electromagnetic field—which protects the atmosphere from being stripped away by the solar wind. Mars used to have a magnetosphere, but the planet lost its dynamo as it cooled. Scientists didn’t think metal ions would be likely to stick around. In fact, Maven wasn’t even looking for them at first. But when the spacecraft—which is in an unusually low orbit, and carries an ultra-sensitive neutral gas and ion mass spectrometer—picked up some metal ions after the comet Siding Spring grazed Mars (at a distance of 82,000 miles) in 2014, the team decided to make keep Maven’s eye out for more. After two years, they’ve realized the ions are a permanent fixture, but behave totally differently than those in Earth’s atmosphere. On Earth, the electromagnetic field and ionospheric winds sort upper atmosphere metal ions into distinct layers. But on Mars, that only happens near super magnetic patches of the planet’s crust. "In most of Mars’ atmosphere, the ions are all mixed up together, and that’s a surprise," says David Brain, Maven co-investigator and atmospheric scientist at the University of Colorado at Boulder. According to Brain, whatever (still mysterious) process keeping all the ions snuggled up together might affect how atmospheric particles leave the upper atmosphere in ways scientists haven’t yet understood. It’ll take studying these metal ions further to see if that’s true. But these ions have implications beyond Mars, too. "We should now be able to find the physics of how this works and apply it to other planets," Benna says. "Most planets with thick atmospheres should have these ions." So this is less the key to Mars’ atmospheric woes and more a tool to compare and contrast different kinds of atmospheres in order to better understand all of them—including Earth’s.</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2017 20:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <category>Science</category>
            <author>Emma.GreyEllis@wired.com</author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
